Be bold. Be brave. Be epic.
Kubo and the Two Strings is a animation, adventure,
family film directed by Travis Knight.
Kubo mesmerizes the people in his village with his magical
gift for spinning wild tales with origami.
When he accidentally summons an evil spirit seeking vengeance, Kubo is forced to go on a quest to solve the mystery
of his fallen samurai father and his mystical weaponry, as well as discover his own magical powers.
Kubo (voice), played by Art Parkinson.
Monkey / Mother (voice), played by Charlize Theron.
Kameyo (voice), played by Brenda Vaccaro.
Hashi (voice), played by Cary-Hiroyuki Tagawa.
Mari (voice), played by Meyrick Murphy.
Hosato (voice), played by George Takei.
Kubo and the Two Strings is a 2016 American stop-motion animated fantasy film
directed by Travis Knight and written by Marc Haimes and Chris Butler.
Produced by Laika, the film stars the voices of  Charlize Theron, Art Parkinson,
Ralph Fiennes, Rooney Mara, George Takei and Matthew McConaughey.
Set in feudal Japan, the film revolves around Kubo, a young boy who wields a
magical musical instrument and whose left eye was stolen during infancy.
Accompanied by an anthropomorphic Japanese macaque charm and a human/stag beetle hybrid, he must embark on a quest to defeat his
mother's baleful twin sisters and his ominous grandfather, the Moon King, who is responsible for stealing his left eye.
Laika's production designer Shannon Tindle pitched the
fantasy story  based on samurais to Knight.
By December 2014, Laika announced that Kubo and the Two Strings would be released in August 2016, with
Knight to direct and produce the project, as well as the voice casting announcement.
He was enthusiastic about the project, owing partly to his affinity towards both the "epic fantasy" genre as well
as Japanese culture in general, despite the studio never having ventured into the genre before.
The stop-motion animation was inspired by Japanese media such as ink wash
painting, ukiyo-e woodblock printing, and origami among others.
Assistance came from 3D printing firm Stratasys who allowed Laika to use
their newest technologies in exchange for feedback on them.
Knight stated that the story for the film was partly inspired
by works of Japanese animator Hayao Miyazaki.
Dario Marianelli, who previously composed the music for Laika's 2014
film The Boxtrolls, composed the film's musical score.
Kubo and the Two Strings premiered at Melbourne International Film Festival on August 13,
2016, and was released by Focus Features in the United States on August 19.
The film received critical acclaim for its craftsmanship and story.
It was a box office disappointment, grossing $78 million
worldwide against a $60 million budget.
The film won the BAFTA Award for Best Animated Film, and was nominated for
Academy Awards for Best Animated Feature and Best Visual Effects.
The film explores themes of japan, samurai, magic, forgiveness, stop motion.